Guide to the Dept. of Floriculture records, 1905-1940.
Dept. of Floriculture records, 1905-1940
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dept. of Floriculture records, 1905-1940.
21-25-137
New York State College of Agriculture. Dept. of Floriculture.
10 cubic ft.
Correspondence, financial records, photographs, course materials, departmental files, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, 1907-1914, of the Dept. of Rural Art, largely that of E. Gorton Davis; correspondence, 1915-1917, of the Dept. of Landscape Art; also correspondence relating to extension, the development and growth of plants, landscaping and city planning, departmental budgets, allotments, and University regulations; departmental photographs and photographs of orchid studies; correspondence of E.A. White (personal and orchid studies); personal and lecture materials of L.H. MacDaniels; and departmental files, mostly relating to pomology.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, 1907-1914, of the Dept. of Rural Art, largely that of E. Gorton Davis; correspondence, 1915-1917, of the Dept. of Landscape Art; also correspondence relating to extension, the development and growth of plants, landscaping and city planning, departmental budgets, allotments, and University regulations; departmental photographs and photographs of orchid studies; correspondence of E.A. White (personal and orchid studies); personal and lecture materials of L.H. MacDaniels; and departmental files, mostly relating to pomology. Correspondents include Bristow Adams, L.H. Bailey, Cornelius Betten, G.E. Burnap, E.O. Fippen, Bryant Fleming, Beverley Galloway, Carl Ladd, J. Horace McFarland, James E. Rice, Paul Stark, W.A. Stocking, A.D. Taylor, Helen Van Keulen, Martha Van Rensselaer, Booker T. Washington, and H.H. Whetzel.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Agriculture.; Adams, Bristow, 1875-1957.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Department of Rural Art, correspondence, 1907-1910 (Box 1)
- Department of Rural Art, correspondence, 1912-1913 (Box 2)
- Department of Rural Art, correspondence, 1912-1913 (Box 3)
- Department of Rural Art, correspondence, A-K, 1914 (Box 4)
- Department of Rural Art, correspondence, L-Z and miscellaneous Departments, 1914 (Box 5)
- Department of Landscape Art, 1915 (Box 6)
- Department of Landscape Art, misc., 1915 (Box 7)
- Department of Landscape Art, misc., 1916 (Box 8)
- Department of Landscape Art, misc., 1916 (Box 9)
- Department of Landscape Art, misc., 1917 (Box 10)
- Department of Landscape Art, misc., 1917 (Box 11)
- Department of Landscape Art, Extension, 1914-1915 (Box 12)
- Department of Landscape Art, Extension, 1916-1917 (Box 13)
- Department of Landscape Art, students, 1914-1917 (Box 14)
- L.H. MacDaniels personal and lecture, 1916-1917 (Box 15)
  One folder personal material, several folders mimeographed lectures and lab notes for Botany and Plant Physiology courses, grading system, exams, botanical data
- Photographs: orchid studies (E.A. White); misc. Departmental (Box 16)
- E.A. White files, orchid studies and personal, 1932-1942 (Box 17)
- L.H. MacDaniels files, 1918-1926 (Box 18)
- L.H. MacDaniels files, 1926-1929? (Box 19)
- L.H. MacDaniels files, 1929-1939 (Box 20)
- L.H. MacDaniels files (Box 21)
- L.H. MacDaniels files, 1939-1940 (Box 22)